Finding Aid for Steve Kagan photograph collection, 1973-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Steve Kagan photograph collection 1973-1976
Kagan, Steve
0.4 linear feet, 1.75 GB
2015005 Aa 2
Photos, 1973-1976, by photographer for The Michigan Daily, University of Michigan student newspaper. Subjects include campus theater, art and music activities and University of Michigan athletics
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Kagan in 2007 (Donor No. 9884 ).
No further additions to the records are currently expected.
The collection is open to research.
Steve Kagan, from Mason, Michigan, attended the University of Michigan from 1972-1976 and worked as a photographer for The Michigan Daily, 1973-1976.
After leaving The Daily, Kagan spent five months as an intern at The Village Voice in New York City and then moved to Chicago where he has worked as a free-lance photographer. His work has appeared frequently in The Chicago Tribune and other local publications as well as regional and national press.
Kagan's photos were featured in a New York Times "Week In Review" article on "Mayor Daley's Mark" on Chicago.(9/12/2010, http://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2010/09/10/weekinreview/20100912-chicago.html)
Kagan lives in Chicago with his wife Ann Marie Lipnski (Michigan Daily 1973-1977, co-editor 1977, former editor of the Chicago Tribune). Kagan has served on the Board of Student Publications.
The Steve Kagan collection consists of 35 mm black and white negatives selected from his personal of work for the Michigan Daily as well as 76 image he selected and digitized from his Daily negatives and 15 images chosen from the Bentley's Michigan Daily records. The digitized images include some concert shots--Aerosmith, Anthony Braxton and 1974 Ann Arbor Jazz and Blues Festival, Hash-Bash and other Diag activities, Daily offices and staff, Gerald Ford meeting with students at the Michigan League, the 1976 Democratic Convention in NYC, a trip to the Indianapolis 500, and a nice shot of Ann Arbor icon "Shakey Jake."
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Kagan, Steve; Braxton, Anthony.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Laver, Rod.; Newcombe, John.; Aerosmith (Musical group); Democratic National Convention (1976: New York, NY); Ann Arbor Jazz and Blues Festival--1974.; Michigan daily.; University of Michigan--Athletic.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Digital files.
- Theater, Music, Arts
  - "Bitch Your Crazy" (play), June 17, 1976, 5 envelopes (Box 1)
  - "People Are Better Off In Zoos" (play), undated, 12 envelope (Box 1)
  - EMU Band Marathon, February 1, 1976, 1 envelope (Box 1)
- U-M Athletics-Men
  - Football
    - Stanford, September 22, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Michigan State, October 13, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Wisconsin, October 29, 1973, 3 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Illinois November 10, 1973, 4 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Iowa, September 14, 1974, 4 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Colorado, September 21, 1974, 5 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Michigan State, October 12, 1974, 4 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Purdue, November 16, 1974, 2 envelopes (Box 1)
    - Pep Rally before Ohio State Game, November 22, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Baseball
    - Penn State, NCAA at EMU, May 22, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Eastern Michigan, May 28, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Basketball
    - Purdue, March 1, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Johnny Orr Basketball camp, July, 7, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Intramural Basketball, February 25, 1976 (Box 1)
    - C.J. Kupec at AP Wire Machine at Daily office, May 29, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Gymnastics
    - Big Ten Meet, March 28, 1975 (Box 1)
    - January 24, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Hockey
    - Unidentified, December 12, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Ohio State, October 26, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Minnesota, January 10, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Swimming
    - unidentified (Box 1)
    - Southern Illinois, January 15, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Wrestling
    - Unidentified, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Wisconsin, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified, February 2, 1973 (Box 1)
- U-M Athletics -- Women
  - Basketball (Box 1)
    - February 28, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Swimming
    - Big Ten Championship, February 9, 19976 (Box 1)
  - Volleyball (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Tennis-Rod Laver vs. John Newcomb, at Crisler Arena, May 30, 1976 (Box 1)
  - WFL Football-Detroit Wheels vs. Birmingham, July 7, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Intramural Frisbee Competition, May 20, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Huron High School basketball cheerleaders, January 1978 (Box 1)
- Michigan Daily Alumni Photographers Project
  - Steve Kagan page
  - Steve Kagan images